

# raveen Kumar Rajer

🛘 (+82) 10-7262-1561 🤝 aravindhanpraveen19@gmail.com 🌴 Portfolio 💆 GitHub 🛅 LinkedIn 💆 Twitter 📢 Medium

Scholar

Seoul, S.Korea

Summary.

l'm a Computer Vision/Al Research Engineer at Neubility. I specialize in developing perception algorithms for self-driving robots. I possess a deep understanding of multiview geometry and a passion for training deep neural networks and optimizing them to make them lightweight. My research interests include deep learning, 3D computer vision and autonomous driving. I love cycling. I enjoy videos of 3Blue1Brown and Veritasium.

## **Work Experience** .

Seoul, S.Korea

Mar. 2023 - Present

- **Neubility** · Computer Vision/AI Research Engineer
- Spearheaded the development of cutting-edge Al-based object detection/segmentation algorithms/handling class imbalance data.
- Leveraged Diffusion-based AI/GAN methods to diversify training data and enhance model performance.
- Proficiently utilized MLOps tools like WandB and MLflow for streamlined development and deployment.
- Developed systems for deidentifying sensitive data, such as human faces and car license plates.
- Developed systems for autolabelling & active learning from incident data.
- Developed systems for leveraging GPT4 Vision API for understanding unlabelled data.
- continually incorporating state-of-the-art approaches to improve system performance. Familiar with Docker/ONNX/TensorRT for deployment.



## KAIST - Vehicullar Intelligence Lab GRADUATE STUDENT RESEARCHER

Daejeon, S.Korea

Mar. 2021 - Feb. 2023

- · Worked on accident prevention ADAS system using OpenCV, Deep learning, Class activation maps, and Segmentation
- Collaborated on PMD path planning and trajectory prediction in heterogeneous traffic.
- Achieved SoTA on relative camera pose estimation problems with deep learning and published at ECCV-Workshop 2022
- Worked on Domain Adaption. Explored Point Cloud Registration/Analysis for further research.

Chennai, India & Gyeongsan,

S.Korea

Nov. 2018 - Feb. 2021

- SL Lumax & SL Corporation · SOFTWARE ENGINEER
- Part Leader for the Indian software verification Team of 24 people at SL Corporation. • Responsible for Software Unit testing (APP+BSP) of Head Lamps LED Driver Module (LDM), Electronic Control Unit (ECU), Integrated Lamp Control Unit (ILCU), Door side Object Detection, Camera Monitoring System, Intelligent battery management system and E-shifters.
- Performed more than 250+ software unit/integration testing projects with the team.
- Professional working knowledge on CodeScroll Controller tester for Unit/Integration testing, VBA, VectorCAST and Source code analysis.
- Certified ISTQB CTFL by Korean Software Testing Qualifications Board.

## **GRADUATE ENGINEERING TRAINEE - SOFTWARE**

Nov. 2017 - Oct. 2018

- Responsible for SiL Unit Test of LED Driver Module (LDM). In-depth BVA for safety critical systems (bitwise/absolute)
- Familiarity with the Embedded C analysis, scripting, Cadence

**Aerobotix** • Robotics and Embedded Systems Intern

Chennai, India

Jan. 2016 - Mar. 2016

- Trained to work with Arduino UNO, Electronics, Sensors, Actuators and Programming microcontrollers.
- Built different robotics applications such as line follower, RC boat, RC hovercraft.
- Hands-on experience on Bluetooth and various modules for navigation.

## **Education**



KAIST (World Ranking 20) . M.S. IN FUTURE VEHICLE PROGRAM

Daejeon, S.Korea

Mar. 2021 - Feb. 2023

- **GPA:**  $3.9/4.3 \approx 95.55\%$
- Subjects: Artificial intelligence/Machine Learning, Deep Learning, Computer Vision, Autonomous Vehicle Systems, Intelligent Transportation Systems, WL Analysis, Operating Systems, Scientific Writing

Chennai, India

Jun. 2013 - May. 2017

Anna University B.E. IN ELECTRICAL AND ELECTRONICS ENGINEERING

- **GPA:**  $8.1/10 \approx 81\%$
- Subjects: Engineering Mathematics, Engineering Graphics, Embedded Systems, Control Systems, Object-Oriented Programming, Circuit Theory, Electrical Machines, Power Electronics



Projects: Lidar Obstacle Detection, Camera & Lidar Fusion, Radar Obstacle Detection, Unscented Kalman Filters - Syllabus - Certificate

Remote

Completed - Nov 2023

Udacity · AI Product Manager Nanodegree

• **Projects:** Data Collection, Model with Google AutoML, Capstone Proposal - Syllabus - Certificate

**MACHINE LEARNING DEVOPS ENGINEER NANODEGREE** 

Remote

Completed - July 2021

Udacity · Self Driving Car Nanodegree

- · Term-1 Projects: Lane detection, Advanced Lane detection, Traffic sign classfier, Behavioral cloning, EKF
- Term-2 Projects: Particle filter, Highway driving, PID Controller, System Integration Syllabus Certificate

Remote

In progress - Present

• Fullstack ML: Predict Customer Churn with Clean Code, Build an ML Pipeline for Short-Term Rental Prices in NYC, Deploying a Machine Learning Model on Heroku with FastAPI, A Dynamic Risk Assessment System - Syllabus

## Skills

Udacity

Computer Vision, Deep Learning, Machine Learning, Robotics, Camera Calibration, Embedded Systems, Software Testing,

Multi-view Geometry, 3D Reconstruction, Computational Photography, Visual Localization, GANs

**Programming** Python, C, MATLAB, C++

Frameworks & Tools

Git, PyTorch, TensorFlow, NumPy, Scikit-Learn, Codescroll Controller Tester, VectorCAST, Pandas, OpenCV, Keras, Matplotlib,

openmm, ROS, Linux, VSCode, Jupyter, Anaconda, Docker, LaTeX

**Languages** Tamil(Native), English(Professional), Korean(TOPIK 1)

## **Honors & Awards**

#### INTERNATIONAL

2012 Recepient, KAIST full funding scholarship for Master's program in Future Vehicle

2019 Recepient, KAIST full funding scholarship for Master's program in Future Vehicle

2019 Recepient, Recipient of Udacity Technology Scholarship powered by Bertelsmann for AI Track - Phase 1

2019 Award, Korea cycling road grand slam given by K-Water for completion of cycling route of 1837KM

2019 Position, Selected for a leadership position of Electronics team of 24 people in SL Corporation.

Gyeongsan, S.Korea

DOMESTIC

Go Green Award, for making an efficient solar vehicle for Asia's largest solar vehicle competition with Team
AATHIRI, ESVC - 2017

Bhimavaram, India

Silver Prize, for the Robotics event of PATHFINDER(Line Follower) in the national level technical symposium VISION organized by Anna University

Chennai, India

. . . .

2013 **School Topper**, Higher secondary public examination

Mayiladuthurai,

## **Publications**

## A Lightweight Domain Adaptive Absolute Pose Regressor Using Barlow Twins Objective

Under review

Praveen Kumar Rajendran, Quoc-Vinh Lai-Dang, Luiz Felipe Vecchietti, Dongsoo Har

2023

## **Reinforcement Learning for Predicting Traffic Accidents**

ICAIIC

Injoon Cho, **Praveen Kumar Rajendran**, Taeyoung Kim, Dongsoo Har

2022

## RelMobNet: End-to-end relative camera pose estimation using a robust two-stage training

ECCV Workshop

**Praveen Kumar Rajendran**, Sumit Mishra, Luiz Felipe Vecchietti, Dongsoo Har

2022

## Sensing accident-prone features in urban scenes for proactive driving and accident prevention

IEEE ITS (IF:9.5)

Sumit Mishra, **Praveen Kumar Rajendran**, Luiz Felipe Vecchietti, Dongsoo Har

2022

2021

SUMIT MISHRA, PRAVEEN KUMAR RAJENDRAN, DONGSOO HAR

## **Projects**

#### Capstone Project: Relative Camera Pose Estimation with Deep Learning

Daejeon, S.Korea

CS570 ARTIFICIAL INTELLIGENCE AND MACHINE LEARNING

Dec. 2021

Achieved SoTA accuracy in Cambridge landmark dataset in comparison to previous deep learning approaches.

#### **Capstone Project: ADAS for accident Prevention**

Daejeon, S.Korea

PD803 PERCEPTION FOR AUTONOMOUS AND CONNECTED VEHICLES

Dec. 2021

ADAS that has the potential to improve driver attention to accident cues at accident hotspot locations. Worked with pandas, PyTorch mmsegmentation, class activation maps and matplotlib extensively.

#### **Capstone Project: End-to-End Autonomous Driving**

Daejeon, S.Korea

**PD551** FUNDAMENTALS OF VEHICLE ELECTRIC SYSTEMS

Dec. 2021

· End-to-End autonomous driving using imitation learning (Inspired by the famous NVIDIA paper) with the data collected from CARLA

#### **Course Projects: Projective Geometry & Computational Photogrammetry**

Daejeon, S.Korea

PD803 PERCEPTION FOR AUTONOMOUS AND CONNECTED VEHICLES

Dec. 2021

· Camera Calibration, 3D Reconstruction in MATLAB

#### Course Projects: CNN Analysis, Regularizations, Sequential modelling

Daejeon, S.Korea

Al502 DEEP LEARNING

lun 202

Deep Convolution Architecture Analysis with multiple optimizers and regularization techniques. Sequential modelling with LSTMs, Transformers, BERT for extractive Question & Answering.

### Course Projects: Construction of Building Blocks of OS with xv6

Daejeon, S.Korea

**EE415** OPERATING SYSTEM

JUII. 2021

• Kernel Threading, Process Scheduler, Nullptr Dereferences and Shared Page Handler, Filesystem Optimization (for small files)

#### **Electric solar vehicle**

Chennai, India

ESVC Feb. 2017

 Made a Conventional Solar vehicle from scratch at low cost with a team of 25 members for the Asia's largest solar vehicle championship. Secured 21st place out of 150 teams. I was the vice captain of the team. Our team was advised by Dr. Kevin ark kumar from BHEL

Robotic Arm Chennai, India

PROJECT AT **AEROBOTIX** 

Mar. 2016

• With the help of flex sensors, various motors and 3D printed objects made a robotic arm which will perform all the actions done by human hand.

### Certifications\_

Aug. 2022 Oxford Machine Learning Summer School 2022, OxML 2022 University of Oxford Apr. 2022 Probabilistic Graphical Models - Representation, Stanford University Mar. 2020 TensorFlow - Data and Deployment Specialization, deeplearning.ai Coursera Jan. 2020 Deep Learning Specialization, deeplearning.ai Dec. 2019 Bertelsmann Technology Scholarship Phase 1, Al Track Udacity Dec. 2019 TensorFlow Developer Professional Certificate, deepleaning.ai Coursera Nov. 2019 Machine Learning, Stanford University Oct. 2019 ISTQB CTFL, Certification **KSTQB** Feb. 2017 Student Industry Project, Solar Power Controller BHEL, Trichy May. 2015 Inplant Training, Power Stability Control SAIL, Salem

## References\_

#### **Prof. Dongsoo Har**

**Associate Professor** 

**KAIST** 

Cho Chun Shik Graduate School of Mobility

A Daejeon, S.Korea

dshar@kaist.ac.kr

#### Dr. Luiz Felipe Vecchietti

Senior Researcher

Data Science Group - IBS

Center for Mathematical & Computational Sciences

♠ Daejeon, S.Korea

✓ Ifelipesv@ibs.re.kr